project-reason.org 2015-06-07

# TITLE nr | Project Reason

Last Updated: 2009.10.26

  1. General Information
  2. Personal Information; Changes To Personal Information
  3. Aggregate Information
  4. Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies
  5. How We Use and Share Personal Information
  6. Your California Privacy Rights
  7. Privacy Preferences/Opt-Out
  8. Security
  9. Children’s Privacy
  10. Changes to Privacy Policy
  11. Third Party Websites
  12. Posts on Message Board
  13. Miscellaneous

## I. General Information

This website, and the various content, features and services offered on this website (collectively, the “Site”), is owned and/or operated by Project Reason (“Project Reason,” “we,” “us,” “our” or similar pronoun). Project Reason is committed to respecting your online privacy and recognizes your need for appropriate protection and management of any personally identifiable information (“Personal Information”) you share with us. Project Reason has established this privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) to let you know what information we may collect from you on the Site and how we may use and share that information. Please take a moment to review the terms of our Privacy Policy. By using the Site, you agree to accept the terms of our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Site. Except as expressly provided herein, this Privacy Policy applies only to information that we collect on the Site and does not apply to information which we may collect by other means.

## II. Personal Information; Changes to Personal Information

Personal Information means any information that may be used to identify an individual, including, but not limited to, first and last name, home or other physical address, telephone number, e-mail address, birth date and year, religious preferences, educational background, occupation, job title, or information about your job/occupation/skills.

In general, you can visit the Site without telling us who you are or revealing any Personal Information about yourself. However, in order to post on the message board, or to become a member or volunteer of Project Reason, we require you to register for an account and/or provide Personal Information. Moreover, other features or services may require you to provide Personal Information. For example, we may collect certain Personal Information if you choose to subscribe to a mailing list, participate in special offers, sweepstakes, contests, or other promotions, or send questions or comments to us via e-mail.

We may also collect certain demographic information (such as gender or age) and information about your interests and preferences (“Preferences Information”). In many cases, such demographic and Preferences Information is optional. In other cases, such as online surveys, we collect this information on an anonymous basis. However, if we link any demographic or Preferences Information to any Personal Information, then such demographic and Preferences Information will be treated as Personal Information under this Privacy Policy.

For some features of the Site, you may be able to submit information about other people. For example, if you sign a friend up for a mailing list, you may submit the recipient’s e-mail address. You represent and warrant that before you submit any other person’s Personal Information to us that you received their written consent to do so. Project Reason will use and store any such information that we collect from you about another person to carry out your request and for our own internal marketing purposes in accordance with this Privacy Policy.  If you or another user does not want to receive promotional e-mails from Project Reason, opt-out instructions are in Section VII below.

## III. Aggregate Information

From time to time, Project Reason may collect general, non-personal, statistical information about the use of the Site, such as how many visitors visit a specific page on the Site, how long they stay on that page and which hyperlinks, if any, they “click” on. We collect this information through the use of “cookies” and other tracking technologies, which are discussed in greater detail below. We collect this information in order to determine which areas of the Site are most popular and to enhance the Site for visitors. We may group this information into aggregate visitor data in order to describe the use of the Site to our existing or potential business partners, sponsors or other third parties, or in response to a government request. Project Reason may also group demographic and Preferences Information and re sponses to surveys that we collect from visitors into aggregate data for the same purposes. However, please be assured that this aggregate data will in no way personally identify you or any other visitors to the Site

## IV. Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies

Some of our web pages utilize “cookies” and other tracking technologies. A cookie is a small text file that a website transfers to an individual’s hard drive for record-keeping purposes. For example, we may use cookies to collect information about website activity and to maintain your experience on our Site. We never save credit card information in cookies. Most browsers allow you to control cookies, including whether or not to accept them and how to remove them. You may set most browsers to notify you if you receive a cookie, or you may choose to block cookies with your browser. However, please be aware that some features of the Site may not function properly or may be slower if you refuse cookies.

Tracking technologies may record information such as Internet domain and host names; Internet protocol (IP) addresses; browser software and operating system types; clickstream patterns; and dates and times that our Site is accessed. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the web. Web servers, the computers that “serve up” webpages, automatically identify your computer by its IP address. We may link the information we record using tracking technologies to Personal Information we collect at the Site for our own internal marketing efforts.  In addition, we reserve the right to use IP addresses and other tracking technologies to identify a visitor only when we feel it is necessary to enforce compliance with the Site’s policies, to protect the Site, our customers or others, or when we believe in good faith that the law requires it.

The Site may also use a technology called “tracer tags”. These also may be referred to as “Clear GIFs” or “Web Beacons”. This technology allows us to understand which pages you visit on the Site. These tracer tags are used to help us optimize and tailor the Site for you and other Site visitors.

Pop-up blockers or stoppers prevent extra pop-up windows (usually advertisements) from opening in your browser. Pop-up blocking software often has negative effects on other “good” software. If you disable JavaScript pop-up ad windows, you may also disable other Site functionality that uses JavaScript. If you’re using a pop-up blocker that allows you to manage a list of “pop-up friendly” sites, please refer to your Help files and add the URL of this Site to your approved list to ensure maximum functionality at the Site.

## V. How We Use and Share Personal Information

**How We May Use Your Personal Information**

With respect to the Personal Information we collect, we may retain and use that information for several purposes. For example, we may use your Personal Information to send e-mails to our mailing list subscribers, enter you into a sweepstakes or contest, respond to your questions, or establish a membership profile for you. We may also use Personal Information to ensure compliance with our policies and applicable law.  We may use your Personal Information to identify you on the Site.  In addition, we may send you periodic communications by e-mail or regular mail, such as news updates, special promotional offers or information on our products or services which may be of interest to you. You may opt-out of receiving these e-mails when you first submit your e-mail.  If you later wish to opt-out of receiving such promotional communications from us at any time, simply follow the instructions in Section VII below. Notwithstanding the foregoing, we reserve the right to send you certain non-promotional communications relating to the Site, such as service announcements, e-mail related to purchases you have made, or similar administrative or transactional messages, without offering you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving them.  (NOTE:  These transactional or administrative e-mails should be limited to members of the Site.  If a user ends his membership, he should no longer receive these e-mails.)

**With Whom We May Share Your Personal Information**

We may share and disclose your Personal Information to third parties for other purposes, as set forth in this Privacy Policy.  For instance, we may sometimes use other businesses to perform certain services for us, such as maintaining the Site and our mailing lists, processing orders and delivering products, sending postal mail and providing marketing assistance and data analysis. We may provide Personal Information to those businesses when that information is necessary for them to complete a requested transaction or otherwise perform their duties. Project Reason will take reasonable steps to ensure that these third party service providers are obligated to protect Personal Information on Project Reason’s behalf in accordance with the standards established in this Privacy Policy.

As Project Reason develops, we may merge with other organizations and member or user information is generally one of the business assets involved in such transactions. Thus, in the event that Project Reason or some or all of its assets are acquired, customer information could be one of the transferred assets.

Project Reason fully cooperates with law enforcement agencies in identifying those who use our services for illegal activities, and may in its sole discretion disclose Personal Information or other information to satisfy any law, regulation, subpoena, or government request, or in connection with litigation. Project Reason reserves the right to release Personal Information or other information about users who we believe are engaged in illegal activities or are otherwise in violation of our Terms of Use Agreement, even without a subpoena, warrant or court order, if we believe in our sole discretion that such disclosure is necessary or appropriate to operate the Site, or to protect the rights or property of Project Reason, its affiliates, or any of their respective officers, directors, or employees, agents, third party content providers, suppliers, sponsors, or licensors. Project Reason also reserves the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities we reasonably believe in our sole discretion to be unlawful.

## VI. Your California Privacy Rights

## VII. Privacy Preferences/Opt-Out

You can access, change and/or update your Personal Information on the Site at any time by accessing the Personal Section of the Message Board.

If you do not want to receive promotional e-mails from Project Reason, please follow one of the two options below: 

  1. You must opt-out of receiving promotional e-mails. When providing your Personal Information, simply change the answer to “No” when asked whether you would like to receive e-mails from Project Reason.
  2. When you receive an e-mail from Project Reason, it will contain a link that allows you to stop the delivery of e-mail messages from us. If you decide to use this opt-out link, you will no longer receive newsletters or promotional e-mails after ten (10) business days; however, you may (as outlined above) continue to receive non-promotional e-mails from us, such as order confirmations.
  3. If you are a member of the Site, you may edit your e-mail preferences in the Profile Section of the Site.

## VIII. Security

Project Reason intends to take reasonable and appropriate steps to protect the Personal Information that you share with us from unauthorized access or disclosure. When you transmit Personal Information from your personal computer and/or mobile device to our servers, your information is protected by both a “firewall” (a combination of computer hardware and software that helps keep unauthorized visitors from accessing information within our computer network) and industry standard SHA-1 and MD5 encryption. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your Personal Information and privacy, we cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you disclose or transmit to us online and cannot be responsible for the theft, destruction, or inadvertent disclosure of your Personal Information.

Some or all of the Personal Information we collect may be stored or processed on computers located in the United States, whose data protection laws may differ from the jurisdiction which you live.  As a result, this information may be subject to access requests from governments, courts, or law enforcement in those jurisdictions according to laws in those jurisdictions.  Subject to applicable laws in such other jurisdictions, we will use reasonable efforts to ensure that appropriate protections are in place to require the data processor in that country to maintain protections on the Personal Information that are equivalent to those that apply in the country in which you live.

If you create an account on the Site, you may be asked to choose a password for your account, in which case your online account information shall be protected by your password. We recommend that you do not disclose your password to any other person. You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your password and account, and are fully responsible for all activities that occur under your password or account.

## IX. Children’s Privacy

This Site is not intended for use by children under the age of 16, and Project Reason does not knowingly collect or use any Personal Information from such children. If we become aware that we have unknowingly collected Personal Information from a child under the age of 16, we will make commercially reasonable efforts to delete such information from our database.

## X. Changes to Privacy Policy

The terms of this Privacy Policy may change from time to time. We will notify you of any material changes to this Privacy Policy by posting a notice on the homepage of the Site for a reasonable period of time after such changes are made that this Privacy Policy has been updated, and by changing the “Last Updated” date at the top of this Privacy Policy. We encourage you to check this page periodically for any changes. Your continued use of the Site following the posting of any material changes to this Privacy Policy constitutes your acceptance of those changes. If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, or believe that Project Reason has acted inconsistently with this Privacy Policy, please [Contact Us](http://www.project-reason.org/contact/).

## XI. Third Party Websites

Please note that you may have cookies placed on your computer by third party websites that refer you to the Site. Although we do not share your Personal Information with these third party websites, they may be able to link certain non-personally identifiable information we transfer to them with Personal Information they previously collected from you. Please review the privacy policies of each website you visit to better understand their privacy practices. In addition, Project Reason would like to inform you that anytime you click on links (including advertising banners), which take you to third party websites, you will be subject to the third parties’ privacy policies.

While we support the protection of our users’ privacy on the Internet, Project Reason expressly disclaims any and all liability for the actions of third parties, including but without limitation to actions relating to the use and/or disclosure of Personal Information by third parties.

## XII. Posts on Message Board

If you use our message board or other public venues on the Site, you will be identified on those venues on the Site by the user name you submit.  Also, some of your profile information, including your location and occupation, also will be public.  Please be aware that the name you choose to provide will be viewable by all users of our message boards or other public venues, so please use caution when choosing your name or providing any profile information.  Information that you provide on message boards, comments posted on the Site, or communications sent to third parties through the Site, or other similar venues may also be viewable by the general Internet public.  We cannot be responsible for any Personal Information you choose to post on public venues and we recommend careful consideration before you post such information.  You agree that you will not disclose Personal Information relating to any other person in a public area of the Site without that person’s express consent.

## XIII. Miscellaneous

This Privacy Policy and the privacy practices of Project Reason will be subject exclusively to the laws of the State of California within the United States. Project Reason makes no representation that this Privacy Policy and our practices comply with the laws of any other country or jurisdiction. Visitors who use the Site and reside outside the United States do so on their own initiative and are responsible for compliance with local laws, if and to the extent local laws are applicable. If you reside outside of the United States, by using our Site, you consent to the processing and use of your information outside your country.
